当你降临于这尘世时
As you come into this world,
某样事物随之而生
something else is also born.
你开启你的人生 它踏上它的征程
You begin your life, and it begins a journey…
向你进发
towards you.
它缓步而行 但从不停止
It moves slowly, but it never stops.
不论你去哪 选择哪条路
Wherever you go, whatever path you take,
它都步步相随
it will follow.
不疾不徐 总是向你走来
Never faster, never slower, always coming.
你会大步奔跑
You will run.
它则悠悠漫步
It will walk.
你会停下休息
You will rest.
它则不会
It will not.
某天 你会在某个地方流连太久
One day, you will linger in the same place too long.
你坐得太稳 或睡得太沉
You will sit too still or sleep too deep…
直到很晚 你才起身离去
And when, too late, you rise to go…
你会注意到身旁出现另一个身影
You will notice a second shadow next to yours.
你的生命在此终结
Your life will then be over.
如果你以为她的死会使我变得脆弱
If you think because she is dead, I am weak,
那你对我知之甚少
then you understand very little.
如果你与她的死亡有关 而毫无惧意
If you were any part of killing her, and you're not afraid,
那你就是个一无所知的蠢货
then you understand nothing at all.
所以奉劝你一句 听好了
So, for your own sake, understand this.
我是博士
I am the Doctor.
我来找你了
I'm coming to find you,
而且我永远不会停止
and I will never, ever stop.
神秘博士
天堂来使
那间屋子里的设备类似于
The equipment in that room is consistent
某种增强版超远程传送装置
with an augmented ultra long-range teleport.
所以我距离出发地不超过一光年
So, I'm not more than a single light year from where I was,
而且还在同一时区
and I'm in the same time zone.
当太阳下山时
When the sun sets,
我可以通过群星推算出准确的方位
I'll be able to establish an exact position by the stars.
到时候你可有的选了
Then you'll have a choice.
现身 露出你的真面目
Come out, show yourself,
或者继续躲藏
or keep on hiding.
克拉拉说了 不要我复仇
Clara said I shouldn't take revenge.
你要知道 我有时候不太听话
You should know, I don't always listen.
这是什么
Oh, what's this?
你是园丁吗 我讨厌园艺
Well, are you gardeners? I hate gardening!
什么样的人才会有支配花朵的情结
What sort of a person has a power complex about flowers?
这是弱者的独裁方式
It's dictatorship for inadequates.
或者换句话说 这就是独裁
Or to put it another way, it's dictatorship.
来吧 快点
Come on! Chop, chop!
博士现在就要见你
The Doctor will see you now!
让我看看你有什么能耐
Show me what you've got!
我刚目睹了至亲好友痛苦离世
I just watched my best friend die in agony.
我的日子不能更糟了
My day can't get any worse.
让我们看看能拿你的小日子怎么办
Let's see what we can do about yours!
我认识你
I know you.
你以前见过你
I've seen you before!
我年轻时会玩心灵感应 有个小技巧
I used to know a trick, back when I was young and telepathic.
显然 你不能跟门建立心灵连接
Clearly, you can't make an actual psychic link with a door,
原因很明显
for one very obvious reason
它们怒火中烧
they're notoriously cross.
想想 作为门的一生 净被人推着过了
I mean, imagine life as a door. People keep pushing past you.
大家总是在敲门 却从不是找你
All of that knocking, but it's never for you.
而且每晚都会被锁住
And you get locked up every night,
如果你能有一点点的善意
so if you're just a little bit nice…
看到没 克拉拉
See, Clara?
宝刀未老
Still got it.
但是我…
But I…
我实在找不到出路了
I can't actually see a way out of this…
我终于无路可逃了 我的一生到此为止
I've finally run out of corridor. There's a life summed up.
这倒新鲜 我害怕了
Now, this is new. I'm scared.
我才意识到 我真的害怕死亡
I just realised that I'm actually scared of dying.
我说了什么吗
Something I said?
我刚说了什么
What did I say?
你为什么停下了
Why did you stop?
很老 非常老
Old. Very old.
极有可能非常非常古老了
Possibly very, very old.
当我还是个小男孩时 有位老妇人过世了
When I was a very little boy, there was an old lady who died.
他们用纱布将她盖住
They covered her in veils,
但天气实在太热了 于是招来了苍蝇
but it was a hot, sunny day, and the flies came.
这一幕造就了我数年的噩梦
It gave me nightmares for years.
那么 谁把我的噩梦放在了这里
So, who's been stealing my nightmares?
为什么把我放在这里
What am I here for?
你一定认识我很久了 对吧
You've known about me for a very long time, right?
那么 这是什么
So, what is it?
是一个陷阱吗
Is it a trap?
是一座监狱吗
Is it a prison?
不是
No!
这是一间拷问室吗
Is it a torture chamber?
我说的对吗
Am I right?
某人真应该再多了解一下
Somebody really should know better.
任何可以建造这里 又能偷走我噩梦的人
Anyone who can put all of this together and steal my bad dreams,
他们应该更清楚
they should know better.
我的那些秘密 没门
The secrets I have - no chance.
我不会说的
No telling, not me.
我跟你说了我很怕死 我也没说谎
I told you I was scared of dying. And I wasn't lying either.
优势就是 我
Advantage - me!
因为你绝对料不到下面这招
Because you won't see THIS coming!
抱歉 我迟到了 跳了个窗子
Sorry, I'm late! Jumped out of a window.
死定了 你想知道我怎么逃脱的吗
Certain death. Don't you want to know how I survived?
来啊 问我
Go on. Ask me!
错 我当然必须要跳
No, of course I had to jump!
在被审讯时 第一条原则就是
The first rule of being interrogated
你是拷问室里唯一不可替代的人
is that you are the only irreplaceable person in the torture chamber.
这里是你的地盘 所以你做主
The room is yours, so work it.
如果他们用死亡威胁你
If they're going to threaten you with death,
那就让他们看看谁才是老大
show them who's boss.
先死一步
Die faster!
你比大多数人更常看见我这么做
You've seen me do that more often than most.
是吧 克拉拉
Isn't that right, Clara?
死亡规则第一条 别死
Rule one of dying - don't.
第二条 放慢速度
Rule two - slow down.
你的生命掌握在自己手中
You've got the rest of your life.
你想得越快 它就会走得越慢
The faster you think, the slower it will pass.
集中精力
Concentrate!
想着你会活下来
Assume you're going to survive.
永远都这么想
Always assume that.
想象你已经活了下来
Imagine you've already survived.
在你的脑海里有一个避难间
There's a storm room in your mind.
锁上门好好思考
Lock the door and think!
这就是我的避难间
This is my storm room.
我总是想象着回到塔迪斯
I always imagine that I'm back in my Tardis,
向你炫耀
showing off,
告诉你我如何逃出生天 让你放声大笑
telling you how I escaped, making you laugh.
我现在就在这么做
That's what I'm doing right now.
我正在坠落 克拉拉
I am falling, Clara.
我濒临死亡
I'm dying.
然后我要向你解释 我是如何活下来的
And I'm going to explain to you how I survived.
我等不及要听听我说了什么了
I can't wait to hear what I say.
没有听众我什么都不是
I'm nothing without an audience.
一线希望 盐
One hope - salt!
我之前好像闻到过
Thought I smelled it earlier.
打破窗户后我就确信了
When I broke the window, I was sure.
带咸味的空气 这座城堡是立于海中的
Salty air. This castle is standing in the sea.
从高处直接落入水中
Diving into water from a great height
不一定能够活下来
is no guarantee of survival.
我需要知道准确的跌落距离和速度
I need to know exactly how far I'm going to fall, and how fast.
你知道我为何扔了板凳吗
Why do you think I threw the stool?
估算落水时间
Fall time to impact…
七秒钟
'Seven seconds.'
因为你料不到下面这招
Because you won't see this coming!
板凳的风阻
The wind resistance of the stool,
大气的密度
the atmospheric density…
本地重力场的强度
The strength of the local gravity.
我是不是拆穿了魔术把戏
Am I spoiling the magic?
我就是干这个的
I work at this stuff, you know?
距离接触水面还有
Should hit the water in about…
0.02秒
0.02 seconds.
保持意识清醒的几率为
The chances of remaining conscious are…
问题一 这是什么地方
我能睡下去吗
Can't I just sleep?
问题二 你说了什么让那个生物停住了
我非要什么都知道吗
Do I have to know everything?
你怎样才能…
克拉拉 我不能每次都…
Clara, I can't always…
赢？？
它一直跟着我 克拉拉
It keeps coming, Clara.
我去哪里它都跟着 为什么
Wherever I go, it follows. Why?
它为什么这样做
Why does it do that?
问错了问题！
不愧是老师 那正确的问题是什么
Always the teacher. What's the right question, then?
不是为何
而是如何
它在跟着我
It's following me.
我去哪里 它都在追踪我
Wherever I go, it's tracking me.
步履缓慢 打着吓人的趔趄
Slowly though. Scary lurching.
吓人
Scary!
这些无处不在的屏幕
These screens everywhere…
时时刻刻告诉我它在哪里
It's showing me exactly where it is all the time,
它到哪里了 离我多近
how far it's got, how near.
因为它是在故意吓我
Because it's trying to scare me!
在我耳边呼吸的音效
Putting its breath on my neck.
这就是目的 这就是它的行为
That's the point! That's what it's doing.
这是个剧院
This is theatre!
全是为了制造恐惧
It's all about fear.
合理假设
Working hypothesis
我正处于一个全自动鬼屋 一个机械迷宫
I'm in a fully automated haunted house. A mechanical maze.
这是一个以吓死我为目标的致命迷箱
It's a killer puzzle box designed to scare me to death,
而我正被困其中
and I'm trapped inside it.
简直是我的圣诞节
Must be Christmas!
又一把铲子
Another spade?
有人想要我挖地
Someone wants me to dig.
克拉拉 你怎么看
What do you think, Clara?
有人在给我提示吗
Is someone trying to give me a hint?
你会怎么做
What would you do?
跟你一样
没错 没错 你当然会这样
Yes. Yes, of course you would.
说白了 这也正是你的死因
Which, let's be honest, is what killed you.
所以
So,
有人在试图告诉我
someone is trying to tell me
这个花园里埋着重要的东西
that there's something important buried in this garden.
这基本上是它们告诉我的第一件事
That's almost the first thing they tried to tell me.
可能是个诡计
Could be a trick.
也可能是前人留下的
Could be one of my predecessors.
因为我不是这里的第一个囚徒 对吧
Because I'm not the first prisoner here, am I?!
所有那些头骨
All those skulls!
不知道他们哪一步走错了
Wonder where they all went wrong.
这么高的建筑
Building this height,
这么缓慢的生物 然后呢
creature that slow, so what…?
一小时
An hour.
三角形力学 你输了
Physics of a triangle. You lose!
所以呢
So?
它会设置陷阱 没关系
It can set traps. That's OK.
我对陷阱最在行了
I'm good at traps.
你现在要去哪儿呢
So, where are you off to?
这里只有唯一的出入口
Only one way in and one way out.
既然你走了
Well, seeing as you're going…
不 不 这不对
No, no. That's not right.
我在第十二号
刚才又差一点
Well, that was another close one.
或者说很有可能
Or it would be,
虽然我最后总会虎口脱险
once I've been and gone and got myself out of it.
这回我是怎么做到的呢
So, how am I going to do that?
来吧 老师 问我问题
Come on, teacher, ask me questions!
别说谎
我真的害怕死亡
I'm actually scared of dying.
问题二 你说了什么让那个生物停下了
真相 没错
The truth, yes.
但不是什么随便的真相 克拉拉
But not any old truth, Clara.
这个地方就是为了吓我而设计的
This whole place is designed to terrify me.
我正在被审问
I'm being interrogated.
它想要的不只是真相 那不够
It's not just truth it wants. That's not enough.
而是忏悔
It's confession.
我必须说出我从没说过的真相
I have to tell truths I've never told before.
这是唯一能阻止它的办法
That's the only thing that stops it.
你看 问题是
You see, the problem is…
克拉拉
Clara…
有些真相我永远不能说出口
There are truths that I can never tell.
无论如何都不行
Not for anything.
但我现在又害怕又孤单
But I'm scared and I'm alone.
孤单
Alone…
而且非常非常害怕
And very, very scared.
我忏悔
I confess.
我离开伽里弗雷不是因为无聊
I didn't leave Gallifrey because I was bored!
那是谎话 一直都是谎话
That was a lie! It's always been a lie!
不够吗 你还想要更多
Not enough? You want more?
我害怕 我逃跑是因为我害怕
I was scared! I ran because I was scared!
这就是你想让我说的吗 这足够真实了吗
Is that what you want me to say? Is that true enough for you?
奇怪的是
It's funny,
你失去某人的那天不是最糟的日子
the day you lose someone isn't the worst.
至少你还有事可做
At least you've got something to do.
最糟的是他们死后不再回来的日子
It's all the days they stay dead.
五十七分钟
57 minutes.
我的世界就是这样运转的 克拉拉
This is how my world works, Clara.
我一秒一秒数着流逝的时间
I tick off the seconds as they pass.
我的生命就是一场倒计时
My life is a countdown.
如果我把这个生物引到城堡的一端
If I draw the creature to one extreme of the castle,
然后我自己跑向另一端
and I run to the other extreme,
我最多可以为自己争取到
I can earn myself a maximum
八十二分钟
of 82 minutes.
有八十二分钟
82 minutes
用来吃饭 睡觉 工作
to eat, sleep and work.
我的工作是寻找十二号房间
My work is finding Room 12.
这个城堡想要我这么做 它在引诱我
The castle wants me to. It's luring me.
数字排列有些混乱
The numbering is a bit confused,
似乎所有房间编号都被打乱了
as if the rooms are all jumbled up.
可能它们会移动
Maybe they move around.
我能看见整个城堡的移动
I saw the whole castle move…
就在我让那生物停下之时
When I made the creature stop.
每个房间 如果我离开足够长的时间
Every room, if I leave it long enough,
就会回到我刚到来时的状态
reverts to its condition at the moment I arrive.
它会自我清理
It tidies up after itself.
就像全自动家政服务
Automated room service.
我认为这整个地方处于一个闭合能量环里
I think this whole place is inside a closed energy loop,
无限循环
constantly recycling.
或者说我在地狱里
Or maybe I'm in Hell?
没关系 我不怕地狱
That's OK. I'm not scared of Hell.
那只不过是坏人的天堂
It's just Heaven for bad people.
但我还要在这里待多久
But how long will I have to be here?
永远吗
Forever?
它一直跟着我
It's always coming.
越来越近
Always closer.
倒计时永远不会停止
The countdown never stops.
但倒计时的终点是什么
But the countdown to what?
每个人的生命中都有两件大事无人记得
There are two events in everybody's life that nobody remembers,
两件所有生物都会经历的大事
two moments experienced by every living thing.
但是 却无人记得其中点滴
Yet, no-one remembers anything about them.
没有人记得自己的出生
Nobody remembers being born…
也没有人记得自己的死亡
and nobody remembers dying.
所以我们才会盯着头骨的眼眶
Is that why we always stare into the eye sockets of a skull?
因为我们在问
Because we're asking,
那是什么感觉
"What was it like?
疼吗
"Does it hurt?
你还在害怕吗
"Are you still scared?"
鸟儿
鸟儿 这跟鸟儿有什么关系
"Bird"? What's "Bird" got to do with it?
这里有鸟儿吗
Are there birds here?
我漏掉了什么 克拉拉
There's something I'm missing, Clara,
而且我觉得是非常可怕的事情
and I think it's something terrible.
有人吗
Hello?
喂 有人在里边吗 有人吗
Hello, is there someone there? Hello!
这是个陷阱 克拉拉
It's a trap, Clara.
诱饵和陷阱
A lure and a trap.
我跟随着为我洒下的面包屑
I'm following breadcrumbs laid out for me.
这是某人的游戏
This is somebody's game…
而我身不由己
And I can't stop playing,
所有来过的人都输了的游戏
a game everybody else has lost.
我知道怎么移动那些墙 克拉拉
I know how to move that wall, Clara,
只要我不停的忏悔
so long as I don't run out of confessions.
但我真正想知道的是…
But what I really want to know is…
是谁摆弄了天上的星星
Who's been playing about with the stars?
它们的位置都错了
They're all in the wrong places,
至少对于这个时区来说
for this time zone, anyway.
我很清楚我没有穿越时间
I know I didn't time travel to get here.
我能感知时间旅行
I can Fell time travel.
如果我不知道
If I didn't know better,
我会以为自己穿越到了七千年后的未来
I'd say I've travelled 7,000 years into the future.
但我十分清楚没有
But I do know better.
所以是谁移动了星辰的位置
So, who moved the stars?
混血
The Hybrid.
远在时间大战之前
Long before the Time War,
时间领主就知道它会到来
the Time Lords knew it was coming,
就像来临的风暴
like a storm on the wind.
有许多预言和故事
There were many prophecies and stories,
事情发生之前就有了传说
legends before the fact.
其中之一就是关于"混血"这种生物
One of them was about a creature called the Hybrid.
半戴立克 半时间领主
Half Dalek, half Time Lord
终极战士
The ultimate warrior.
但它会站在哪一边
But whose side would it be on?
它会带来和平还是毁灭
Would it bring peace or destruction?
它真实存在 还是无端的幻想
Was it real, or a fantasy?
我忏悔
I confess,
我知道"混血"真实存在
I know the Hybrid is real.
我知道它在哪里 它是什么
I know where it is, and what it is.
我忏悔 我很害怕
I confess, I'm afraid.
家
当然了
Of course!
最后一片拼图
The last square on the board.
不然还能是什么呢
What else would it be?
塔迪斯
The Tardis.
离我只有一次忏悔的距离
One confession away.
阿兹班铁
Azbantium.
比钻石硬四百倍
400 times harder than diamond.
厚二十尺
20 feet thick.
唯一的出口
The way out.
鸟儿
Bird!
就是那个时候 我想起来了
That's when I remember!
永远都是那个时候
Always then.
每次都是同一个时刻
Always…then.
永远都是那个确切的瞬间
Always EXACTLY then!
我不能继续下去了 克拉拉 我做不到
I can't keep doing this, Clara! I can't!
为什么总是我
Why is it always me?
为什么永远轮不到别人
Why is it never anybody else's turn?!
怎样才能…
赢
我就不能输一次吗
Can't I just lose?
就这一次
Just this once?!
简单 会很简单
Easy. It would be easy.
超级简单
It would be SO easy.
只需要告诉他们
Just tell them.
只要告诉想知道的人关于"混血"的一切
Just tell them, whoever wants to know, all about the Hybrid.
我不能继续下去了
I can't keep doing this.
我做不到
I can't…
我不能总是这样选择
I can't always do this!
这不公平
It's not fair!
克拉拉 这太不公平了
Clara, it's just not fair!
我为什么不能输
Why can't I just lose?!
不
但是我记得 克拉拉
But I can remember, Clara.
你不懂
You don't understand,
我全都记得
I can remember it all.
每一次
Every time.
但你还是走了
And you'll still be gone.
不管我做什么
Whatever I do…
你永远不会再回来了
You still won't be there.
博士
Doctor…
不是只有你一个人失去过某人
You are not the only person who ever lost someone.
这是所有人都会经历的事
It's the story of everybody.
克服它
Get over it.
打败它
Beat it.
冲破枷锁
Break free.
博士 是时候了
Doctor, it's time.
站起来
Get up, off your arse…
去赢吧
And win!
又见面了
Hello again.
不会再有忏悔了 抱歉
No more confessions, sorry.
但是我会告诉你…真相
But I will tell you…the truth.
混血生物是个非常危险的秘密
The Hybrid is a very dangerous secret.
一个非常非常危险的秘密 必须守住
A very, very dangerous secret and it needs to be kept!
所以 我什么都不会告诉你
So, I'm telling you nothing.
没有半点信息
Nothing at all.
相反 我要做一件更激进的事
Instead, I'm going to do something far worse.
我要离开这里
I'm going to get out of here,
找出当初是谁把我放到这里的
and find whoever put me here in the first place,
不管他们准备做些什么 我都会阻止
and whatever they're trying to do, I'm going to…stop it!
这也许会花费一点时间
But it might take me a little while,
所以你想不想听我讲个故事
so do you want me to tell you a story?
格林兄弟 有趣的两个家伙
The Brothers Grimm, lovely fellas…
我们加入过同一个飞镖队
They're on my darts team.
据他们说
According to them,
曾经有一位皇帝
there's this emperor
他问一位牧童
and he asks this shepherd's boy…
"永恒一共有多少秒"
"How many seconds in eternity?"
人们总是轻看时间领主
People always get it wrong with Time Lords.
我们命硬得很
We take forever to die.
即便我们伤重到无法重生
Even if we're too injured to regenerate,
身体里的每一个细胞也会不断努力
every cell in our bodies keeps trying.
真正的死亡
Dying properly,
可能需要好几天
can take days.
这就是为什么我们喜欢在同族人身边死去
That's why we like to die among our own kind.
他们知道不要提前下葬
They know not to bury us early.
我想 以我现在的状态
I think, in my current condition…
可能需要大约一天半的时间
It'll take me about a day and a half
来爬到塔顶
to reach the top of the tower.
我想
I think.
如果我幸运的话
If I'm lucky…
我有一天半的时间
I have a day and a half.
我必须要这么做 克拉拉
I have to do this, Clara.
这是唯一的办法
It's the only way.
我必须坚强起来
I have to be strong.
我从一开始就应该知道的
I should have known from the very beginning.
显而易见
Of course.
你的画像
The portrait of you,
我噩梦里走出来的怪物
the creature from my own nightmares…
这是为我私人订制的拷问室
This place is my own, bespoke torture chamber…
专门针对我一个人
Intended for me only,
至于水里的那些头骨
and all those skulls in the water…
我自己的地狱里 怎么可能有别的囚犯
How could there be other prisoners…in my hell?
答案显而易见
The answer, of course,
从未有过其他的囚犯
is there never were any other prisoners.
那些星星
And the stars…
也没有错位
They weren't in the wrong place…
我也没有进行时间旅行
And I haven't time travelled.
我只是在这里
I've just been here
停留了很久很久
a very, very long time.
每个房间都会重启
Every room resets.
记得我跟你说过的吗
Remember I told you that?
每个房间都会回到初始状态
Every room reverts to its original condition.
逻辑上讲 传送器也是如此
Logically, the teleporter should do the same.
传送器 有趣的词
"Teleporter" - fancy word.
其实就像3D打印机
Just like 3D printers, really,
只不过这个要先分解物质提取信息
except they break down living matter and information,
然后进行传送
and transmit it.
你所需要做的 就是提供能量
All you have to do is add energy.
房间已经重启
The room has reset,
回到了我刚来时的初始状态
returned to its original condition when I arrived.
这意味着有一个我的备份
That means there's a copy of me
还存在硬盘上面
still in the hard drive.
那个我
Me,
完好如新 和我最初到来时一样
exactly as I was…When I first got here…
就在七千年前
7,000 years ago.
我只需要一些能量
All I have to find is some energy.
要制造能量
And all you need for energy…
只要找到燃料就行
Is something to burn.
鸟儿
我能这样继续多久 克拉拉
How long can I keep doing this, Clara?
燃烧旧我
Burning the old me…
来创造新我
To make a new one?
如果你以为她的死会使我变得脆弱
If you think because she's dead, I am weak,
那你对我知之甚少
then you understand very little.
如果你与她的死亡有关 而毫无惧意
If you were any part of killing her and you're not afraid,
那你就是个一无所知的蠢货
then you understand nothing at all.
所以奉劝你一句 听好了
So, for your own sake, understand this.
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
我来找你了
I'm coming to find you,
而且我永远不会停止
and I will never, ever stop.
因为你绝对料不到下面这招
Because you won't see this coming!
如果我不知道
If I didn't know better,
我会以为自己穿越到了七千年后的未来
I'd say I've travelled 7,000 years into the future.
"永恒一共有多少秒"
"How many seconds in eternity?"
如果我不知道
If I didn't know better,
我会以为自己穿越到了一万二千年后的未来
I'd say I've travelled 12,000 years into the future.
"永恒一共有多少秒"
"How many seconds in eternity?"
然后牧童说
And the shepherd's boy…
六十万年后的未来
600,000 years into the future.
"永恒一共有多少秒"
"How many seconds in eternity?"
然后牧童说
And the shepherd's boy says…
一百二十万年后的未来
1,200,000 years into the future.
然后牧童说
And the shepherd's boy says…
两百万年后的未来
Two million years into the future.
然后牧童说
And the shepherd's boy says…
两千万年后的未来
20 million years into the future.
然后牧童说
And the shepherd's boy says…
"有那么一座钻石山"
"There's this mountain of pure diamond.
"爬过去要一小时 绕过去要一小时"
"It takes an hour to climb it, and an hour to go around it!"
五千二百万年
52 million years.
"每隔一百年 一只小鸟飞来
"Every hundred years, a little bird comes
"在钻石山上磨砺它的鸟喙"
"And sharpens its beak on the diamond mountain…"
大约十亿年
Nearly a billion years.
"待到这整座山都被磨平"
"And when the entire mountain is chiselled away,
"永恒的第一秒才刚过去"
"The first second of eternity will have passed!"
超过十亿年
Well over a billion years.
你定然以为那是很长一段时间
You must think that's a hell of a long time.
二十亿年
Two billion years.
说真的 我觉得那真是…
Personally, I think that's a hell of a…
我觉得 那真是一只好鸟
Personally, I think that's a hell of a bird.
到城里去
Go to the city.
找一个有地位的人
Find somebody important.
告诉他们 我回来了
Tell them, I'm back.
告诉他们 我知道他们的所作所为
Tell them, I know what they did,
还有 我马上就到
and I'm on my way.
如果他们问起我是谁
And if they ask you who I am,
告诉他们 我是远方的来客
tell them, I came the long way round.
你应该还能听到我
You can probably still hear me…
那我就将这秘密告诉你
So just between ourselves…
你误解了预言
You've got the prophecy wrong.
混血并没有一半的戴立克血统
The Hybrid is not half Dalek.
不存在半血戴立克
Nothing is half Dalek.
戴立克绝不允许这样的物种存在
The Daleks would never allow that.
混血必将战胜伽里弗雷
The Hybrid destined to conquer Gallifrey
而将它的废墟踩在脚下的
and stand in its ruins…
就是我
is me.